<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!--Agricultural use settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>OccurrencePatternsTier</Id>
    <Name>Occurrence patterns tier</Name>
    <Description>Specifies the occurrence patterns should should be treated/modelled according to a pre-defined tier or
      custom.</Description>
    <ValueType>OccurrencePatternsTier</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseOccurrenceFrequencies</Id>
    <Name>Use occurrence frequencies</Name>
    <Description>Account for occurrence frequencies for combinations of food and substance in the exposure calculations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseOccurrencePatternsForResidueGeneration</Id>
    <Name>Use occurrence patterns for generating simulated samples</Name>
    <Description>When selected, this simulated samples will be based on occurrence patterns.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAgriculturalUseTable</Id>
    <Name>Use occurrence frequencies for imputation</Name>
    <Description>
      Use of occurrence frequencies (e.g., agricultural use frequencies) is relevant for imputation of censored values
      in the concentration data.
      Part of the observed censored values and missing values may be imputed with zero when the occurrence frequency is
      smaller than 100%.
      If checked, occurrence frequencies are expected as input of this action, otherwise 100% potential presence is
      assumed for all substances on all foods.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SetMissingAgriculturalUseAsUnauthorized</Id>
    <Name>Associate the unspecified percentage with no-occurrence for foods with at least one specified occurrence
      pattern</Name>
    <Description>
      If checked, for foods with at least one specified occurrence pattern, unspecified occurrence patterns for the same
      food are assumed to be associated with no use.
      If unchecked, all substances are considered to be authorised (potentially present in samples).
      Note that this setting cannot be used for foods that have no specified AUs. These foods have 100% potential
      presence of all substances.
      To declare all AUs on such a food un-authorised, include an empty AU with percentage 100% in the AU data table
      (i.e., use an AU for this food, without specifying substances in the AU Substances table)
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAgriculturalUsePercentage</Id>
    <Name>Apply occurrence pattern percentages</Name>
    <Description>If checked, use the percentages of potential presence as specified by the occurrence patterns.
      If unchecked, 100% potential presence in samples is assumed for all substances identified by the occurrence
      patterns.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ScaleUpOccurencePatterns</Id>
    <Name>Scale up use frequency to 100%</Name>
    <Description>Scale up use frequency to 100%.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictOccurencePatternScalingToAuthorisedUses</Id>
    <Name>Restrict use percentage up-scaling to authorised uses</Name>
    <Description>Restrict use percentage up-scaling to authorised uses.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
