<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!--Concentration model settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConcentrationModelChoice</Id>
    <Name>Concentration model tier</Name>
    <Description>Specifies the module settings should be set according to a pre-defined tier or using custom settings.</Description>
    <ValueType>SettingsTemplateType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DefaultConcentrationModel</Id>
    <Name>Default concentration model</Name>
    <Description>
      The concentration model type that will be used as default for all food/substance combinations.
      If this model type cannot be fitted, e.g., due to a lack of data, a simpler model will be chosen automatically as
      a fall-back.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>ConcentrationModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConcentrationModelTypesFoodSubstance</Id>
    <Name>Concentration model types per food-substance combination</Name>
    <Description>
      The concentration model types used for food/substance combinations.
    </Description>
    <IsList>true</IsList>
    <SystemType>ConcentrationModelTypeFoodSubstance</SystemType>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsFallbackMrl</Id>
    <Name>Include MRL fallback model</Name>
    <Description>Use the MRL as fallback model in case the occurrence data is insufficient for other concentration
      modelling options.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FractionOfMrl</Id>
    <Name>MRL Factor (f x MRL)</Name>
    <Description>Use f x MRL as concentration estimate of the MRL models.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NonDetectsHandlingMethod</Id>
    <Name>Censored values replacement</Name>
    <Description>How to replace censored values (when not co-modelled, as in censored models).</Description>
    <ValueType>NonDetectsHandlingMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FractionOfLOR</Id>
    <Name>Factor f (f x LOR or f x LOD or LOD + f x (LOQ - LOD)</Name>
    <Description>Replace censored values by Limit of reporting (LOR), Non-detects (LOD) or Non-quantifications (LOQ)
      times this factor. Constant (f), e.g. 0.5.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictLorImputationToAuthorisedUses</Id>
    <Name>Restrict LOR imputation to authorised uses</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether imputation of factor x LOR should be limited to authorised uses only.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictWaterImputationToApprovedSubstances</Id>
    <Name>Restrict water imputation to approved substances</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether imputation of water should be limited to approved substances only.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsProcessing</Id>
    <Name>Apply processing factors</Name>
    <Description>Specified in table ProcessingFactor. If checked, processing factors are applied. Concentrations in the
      consumed food may be different from concentrations in the modelled food in monitoring programs (typically raw
      food) due to processing, such as peeling, washing, cooking etc. If unchecked, no processing information is used.
      This is in most (though not all) cases a worst-case assumption</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsSampleBased</Id>
    <Name>Sample based</Name>
    <Description>Include co-occurrence of substances in samples in simulations. If checked, substance residue
      concentrations are sampled using the correlations between values on the same sample. If unchecked, any correlation
      between substances is ignored, substance residue concentrations are sampled ignoring the correlations between
      values on the same sample.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImputeMissingValues</Id>
    <Name>Impute missing values from available values (if unchecked, missing values are imputed with 0)</Name>
    <Description>If checked, in procedure of EFSA Guidance 2012, Appendix 1, impute missing values using substance based
      concentration models. If unchecked, missing values are imputed by 0.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CorrelateImputedValueWithSamplePotency</Id>
    <Name>Correlate imputed values with sample potency</Name>
    <Description>If checked, in procedure of EFSA Guidance 2012, Appendix 1, correlate high imputed values with high
      cumulative potency samples. If unchecked, random imputation.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsSingleSamplePerDay</Id>
    <Name>Consumptions on the same day come from the same sample</Name>
    <Description>If checked, in procedure of EFSA Guidance 2012, section 4.1.1, all consumptions of a raw commodity of
      an individual on the same day are assumed to come from the same sample. If unchecked, all consumptions of a raw
      commodity of an individual on the same day are assumed to come from different samples.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsCorrelation</Id>
    <Name>Maximise co-occurrence of high values in simulated samples</Name>
    <Description>Within each pattern of substance presence. If checked, substance residue concentrations are sorted
      within co-occurrence patterns of substances on the same samples. After sorting, high residue values occur more
      frequently on the same sample. This choice is conservative. If unchecked, substance residue concentrations are
      sampled at random, ignoring any co-occurrence patterns of substances on the same samples. This choice is less
      conservative.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConcentrationModelTypesPerFoodCompound</Id>
    <Name>ConcentrationModelTypesPerFoodCompound</Name>
    <Description>Concentration model types per food substance</Description>
    <ValueType>ConcentrationModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
