<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!-- Consumption selection settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConsumerDaysOnly</Id>
    <Name>Restrict population to consumers or consumer days only</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the population should be restricted to the individuals (chronic) or individual days
      (acute) that have non-zero consumption.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictPopulationByFoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Restrict population to consumers or consumer days with consumptions of specific foods</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the population should be restricted to the individuals (chronic) or individual days
      (acute) consuming any of the foods of the specified subset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalFoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Selected foods-as-eaten</Name>
    <Description>Set of consumed foods that are of particular interest for restricting the consumers / consumption days.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
    <IsList>true</IsList>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictConsumptionsByFoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Consumption subset: restrict to consumptions of specific foods</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then the consumptions are restricted to those of the specified food-as-eaten subset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Selected foods-as-eaten</Name>
    <Description>Set of consumed foods that are of particular interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
    <IsList>true</IsList>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsDefaultSamplingWeight</Id>
    <Name>Ignore sampling weights</Name>
    <Description>If checked, individual sampling weights are not used (sampling weight = 1). If unchecked, the specified
      sampling weights are used.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseHbmSamplingWeights</Id>
    <Name>Use sampling weights</Name>
    <Description>If checked, individual sampling weights are used. If unchecked, the individual sampling weights are not
      in the calculations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsPerPerson</Id>
    <Name>Report consumptions and exposures per individual instead of per kg body weight</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether body weights should be ignored and consumptions and exposures should be expressed per
      individual. Otherwise, the consumptions and exposures are per kg body weight.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseBodyWeightStandardisedConsumptionDistribution</Id>
    <Name>Use standardised consumption distributions before calculation of single values</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether single values are calculated on individual consumptions standardised with body weight
      and then multiplied by the mean body weight. Otherwise, single values are calculated on the original consumptions
      (per day). Note that both methods lead to different estimates for the single value.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExcludeIndividualsWithLessThanNDays</Id>
    <Name>Exclude individuals with less than N days</Name>
    <Description>Filter out all individuals with less than N survey days.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MinimumNumberOfDays</Id>
    <Name>N (number of days in survey)</Name>
    <Description>Specify the nominal number of days in the survey to filter out all individuals with less than N survey
      days.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
    <IsInteger>true</IsInteger>
    <DefaultValue>2</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MatchIndividualSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
    <Name>Match consumer selection to population definition options</Name>
    <Description>Match consumption data to population definition. Use population definitions (default), ignore all
      population definitions or use a selection of properties.</Description>
    <ValueType>IndividualSubsetType</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>MatchToPopulationDefinition</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MatchHbmIndividualSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
    <Name>Match HBM individuals selection to population definition options</Name>
    <Description>Match HBM individuals selection to population definition. Use population definitions (default), ignore
      all population definitions or use a selection of properties.</Description>
    <ValueType>IndividualSubsetType</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>MatchToPopulationDefinition</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NameCovariable</Id>
    <Name>Covariable name</Name>
    <Description>Specify the name of the covariable.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NameCofactor</Id>
    <Name>Cofactor name</Name>
    <Description>Specify the name of the cofactor.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
