<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!-- Food conversions settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseProcessing</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using processing info</Name>
    <Description>
      Try to find the code in the processing table. When a match is found, then also a food translation record
      is searched for to also include information on weight reduction/increase (translation proportion).
      Warning: the processing step is deprecated and is currently only maintained for backwards compatibility reasons.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseComposition</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using food translations</Name>
    <Description>
      Try to find food translations for the current food (i.e. the ingredients of a composite food). This may
      result in one or more food codes for ingredients, and the iterative algorithm will proceed with each of the
      ingredient food codes in turn.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>false</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TotalDietStudy</Id>
    <Name>Total diet study concentration data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether exposure is based on sampling data from total diet studies.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseMonitoringDataForTDS</Id>
    <Name>Use TDS monitoring data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether monitoring data are used in addition to total diet study data.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseTdsComposition</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using TDS food sample compositions</Name>
    <Description>
      Try to find the code in the TDS food sample compositions table (idFood), a default translation proportion
      of 100% is assumed. The iterative algorithm will proceed with a TDS food (column idTDSFood) sample.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseReadAcrossFoodTranslations</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using food extrapolations</Name>
    <Description>
      Try to find read across codes. If unchecked, read across table is ignored, default is 'Use
      read across info'. E.g. for pineapple no measurements are found but by specifying that pineapple is converted to
      FruitMix (with a default proportion of 100%), the TDS sample concentration value of FruitMix will be used for
      pineapple (as-eaten or as ingredient).
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseMarketShares</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using market shares</Name>
    <Description>Try to find subtype codes, e.g. 'xxx$*' in the market shares table.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseSubTypes</Id>
    <Name>Allow market shares not summing to 100%</Name>
    <Description>
      Specify whether to rescale market share percentages that do not sum to 100%. If checked, then foods
      with marketshares not summing to 100% are allowed. If not, then these foods are ignored in the analysis.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseSuperTypes</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion to supertypes</Name>
    <Description>
      Try to find supertypes, e.g. 'xxx$yyy' is converted to 'xxx'. If checked, allows for linkage of consumed foods
      coded at a lower hierarchical level to foods with measured concentrations at a higher hierarchical level e.g.
      consumed is Apple (code PF$Apple) --&gt; measured is Pome Fruit (code PF). Note: food codes are split on '$'.
      Measurements of substances on food are available at a less detailed food coding level than consumption data.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseDefaultProcessingFactor</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using default processing</Name>
    <Description>
      Allow conversion from processed to unprocessed foods. Either by matching to processing types specified as substrings
      separated using a '-' character or by matching FoodEx2 facet strings (separated by a '#' character) to processing types.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>true</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SubstanceIndependent</Id>
    <Name>Substance independent conversion</Name>
    <Description>Conversion of foods is independent of the substance.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
