<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!-- Food conversion settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseProcessing</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using processing info</Name>
    <Description>
      Warning, the processing step is deprecated and is currently only maintained for backwards compatibility reasons.
      See documentation for more details how processed foods are converted in the upgraded conversion algorithm.
      Step 2a: try to find the code in the processing table. Try to find the code in the FoodTranslation table (step 3a)
      to account for weight reduction/increase (translation proportion).
      If unchecked (default), processing table is ignored. If successful, restart at step 1.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseComposition</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using food translations</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 3a: try to find food translations for the current food (i.e., the ingredients of a composite food). This may
      result in one or more food codes for ingredients, and the iterative algorithm will proceed with each of the
      ingredient food codes in turn.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>true</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseTdsComposition</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using TDS food sample compositions</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 3b: try to find the code in the TDS food sample compositions table (idFood), a default translation proportion
      of 100% is assumed. The iterative algorithm will proceed with a TDS food (column idTDSFood) sample.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseReadAcrossFoodTranslations</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using food extrapolations</Name>
    <Description>Step 3c: try to find read across codes. If unchecked, read across table is ignored, default is 'Use
      read across info'. E.g. for pineapple no measurements are found but by specifying that pineapple is converted to
      FruitMix (with a default proportion of 100%), the TDS sample concentration value of FruitMix will be used for
      pineapple (as-eaten or as ingredient). If successful, restart at step 1.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseMarketShares</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using market shares</Name>
    <Description>Step 4: try to find subtype codes, e.g. 'xxx$*' in the market shares table.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseSubTypes</Id>
    <Name>Allow market shares not summing to 100%</Name>
    <Description>Specify whether to rescale market share percentages that do not sum to 100%. If checked, then foods
      with marketshares not summing to 100% are allowed. If not, then these foods are ignored in the analysis.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseSuperTypes</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion to supertypes</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 5: try to find supertypes, e.g. 'xxx$yyy' is converted to 'xxx' (optional, check box if you want to use
      this). If checked, allows for linkage of consumed foods coded at a lower hierarchical level to foods with measured
      concentrations at a higher hierarchical level e.g. consumed is Apple (code PF$Apple) --&gt; measured is Pome Fruit
      (code PF). Note: food codes are split on '$'. Measurements of substances on food are available at a less detailed
      food coding level than consumption data. MCRA allows to use the concentration data of a supertype for all
      underlying food codes. If successful, restart at step 1.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseDefaultProcessingFactor</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using default processing factors</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 6: remove processing part. If unchecked, no default processing factors are assumed, default is 'Use default
      processing factors'. If successful, restart at step 1.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>true</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SubstanceIndependent</Id>
    <Name>Conversion is substance independent</Name>
    <Description>Conversion of foods is independent of the substance.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
