<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!-- Hazard characterisations settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDoseLevelType</Id>
    <Name>Target level</Name>
    <Description>
      Select to express hazard characterisations at external dose, internal concentration or internal dose (systemic) level. For an aggregate
      assessment, that is dietary and nondietary exposure data are combined, the target dose level is always internal concentration or internal dose (systemic).
      When only dietary exposures are available, the target dose level is optional, i.c. external (administered) dose, internal (tissue) concentration or internal (absorbed) dose.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>TargetLevelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictToCriticalEffect</Id>
    <Name>Consider critical effect</Name>
    <Description>
      Specifies whether the analysis should look at critical effects such as specified in the Hazard characterisation 
      data source.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDosesCalculationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Point of departure source</Name>
    <Description>
      Point of departure source for computing the hazard characterisations: from points of departure (data), dose response models or both.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>TargetDosesCalculationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>PointOfDeparture</Id>
    <Name>Expression type</Name>
    <Description>
      Specifies how hazard characterisations are expressed: as BMD, as NOAEL, or the expression type is ignored.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>PointOfDeparture</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDoseSelectionMethod</Id>
    <Name>Selection method in case of multiple candidate hazard characterisations</Name>
    <Description>
      Choose either the most toxic (default) or an aggregated hazard characterisation when in nominal runs
      there are multiple available candidates. In uncertainty runs, multiple candidates are resampled.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>TargetDoseSelectionMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImputeMissingHazardDoses</Id>
    <Name>Impute missing hazard characterisations</Name>
    <Description>
      If checked, missing hazard characterisations are imputed based on Munro NOELs or on other available
      points of departure.
    </Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardDoseImputationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Imputation method</Name>
    <Description>
      Imputation of Hazard characterisations: use low percentile (P5) or unbiased central estimate from
      either the Munro set or the available POD collection.
    </Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>HazardDoseImputationMethodType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseBMDL</Id>
    <Name>Use lower limit of BMD</Name>
    <Description>
      Use the lower uncertainty limit of the benchmark dose. For an uncertainty run, the lower limit is the p5 of the bootstrap sample,
      otherwise it is a parametric estimate based on the parameters of the dose response curve.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseIntraSpeciesConversionFactors</Id>
    <Name>Use intra-species factors</Name>
    <Description>Use intra-species conversion factors (default value, e.g. 10, or data).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>AdditionalAssessmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Additional assessment factor</Name>
    <Description>Additional assessment factor for extrapolation of PODs to (human) hazard characterisations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>100</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAdditionalAssessmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Use additional assessment factor</Name>
    <Description>Use additional assessment factor for extrapolation of PODs to (human) hazard characterisations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Aggregate</Id>
    <Name>Include dietary and non-dietary routes of exposure</Name>
    <Description>
      Specifies whether the assessment involves both dietary and non-dietary (oral, inhalatory or dermal)
      routes of exposure.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardCharacterisationsConvertToSingleTargetMatrix</Id>
    <Name>Restrict to single target</Name>
    <Description>
      Restrict to one biological matrix when computing substance hazard characterisations at the internal level.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetMatrix</Id>
    <Name>Target biological matrix</Name>
    <Description>The target biological matrix (internal compartment) for which exposures are computed.</Description>
    <ValueType>BiologicalMatrix</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>Undefined</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HCSubgroupDependent</Id>
    <Name>Use hazard characterisations subgroup</Name>
    <Description>
      Hazard characterisations are dependent on subgroups (e.g. based on age or gender, see dataformats HCSubgroups).
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>true</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
