<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!-- Hazard characterisations (Target hazard doses) calculation settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDoseLevelType</Id>
    <Name>Target level</Name>
    <Description>Select to express hazard characterisations at external or internal exposure level. For an aggregate
      assessment, that is dietary and nondietary exposure data are combined, the target dose level is always internal.
      When only dietary exposures are available, the target dose level is optional, i.c. external or internal. </Description>
    <ValueType>TargetLevelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDosesCalculationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Method</Name>
    <Description>Choose method for computing the hazard characterisations: from in-vivo or in-vitro points of departure
      or both.</Description>
    <ValueType>TargetDosesCalculationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>PointOfDeparture</Id>
    <Name>Expression type</Name>
    <Description>Specifies how hazard characterisations are expressed: as BMD, as NOAEL, or the expression type is
      ignored.</Description>
    <ValueType>PointOfDeparture</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictToCriticalEffect</Id>
    <Name>Consider critical effect</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the analysis should look at critical effects such as specified in the Hazard
      characterisation data source.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDoseSelectionMethod</Id>
    <Name>Selection method in case of multiple candidate hazard characterisations</Name>
    <Description>Choose either the most toxic (default) or an aggregated hazard characterisation when in nominal runs
      there are multiple available candidates. In uncertainty runs, multiple candidates are resampled.</Description>
    <ValueType>TargetDoseSelectionMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImputeMissingHazardDoses</Id>
    <Name>Impute missing hazard characterisations</Name>
    <Description>If checked, missing hazard characterisations are imputed based on Munro NOELs or on other available
      points of departure.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardDoseImputationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Imputation method</Name>
    <Description>Imputation of Hazard characterisations: use low percentile (P5) or unbiased central estimate from
      either the Munro set or the available POD collection.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>HazardDoseImputationMethodType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseDoseResponseModels</Id>
    <Name>Use BMDs from dose response models</Name>
    <Description>If checked, preferably BMDs from dose response models will be used. If these data are not available,
      other POD data are used.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseBMDL</Id>
    <Name>Use lower limit of BMD</Name>
    <Description>
      If checked, the lower limit of the benchmark dose is used. For an uncertainty run, the lower limit is the p5 of the bootstrap sample, 
      otherwise it is a parametric estimate based on the parameters of the dose response curve.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseInterSpeciesConversionFactors</Id>
    <Name>Use inter-species conversions</Name>
    <Description>Use inter-species conversion factors (default value, e.g. 10, or data).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseIntraSpeciesConversionFactors</Id>
    <Name>Use intra-species factors</Name>
    <Description>Use intra-species conversion factors (default value, e.g. 10, or data).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAdditionalAssessmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Use additional assessment factor</Name>
    <Description>Use additional assessment factor for extrapolation of PODs to (human) hazard characterisations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>AdditionalAssessmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Additional assessment factor</Name>
    <Description>Additional assessment factor for extrapolation of PODs to (human) hazard characterisations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardCharacterisationsConvertToSingleTargetMatrix</Id>
    <Name>Convert to single target</Name>
    <Description>
      Convert all substance hazard characterisations from other biological matrices to the same target biological matrix.
      This conversion is applied when the number of substances measured on the target biological matrix is limited.
      Substances measured on other matrices can be converted using kinetic conversion models.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetMatrix</Id>
    <Name>Biological matrix</Name>
    <Description>The target biological matrix (internal compartment) for which exposures are computed.</Description>
    <ValueType>BiologicalMatrix</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HCSubgroupDependent</Id>
    <Name>Hazard characterisations are dependent on age</Name>
    <Description>
      Hazard characterisations are dependent on age or gender, see dataformats HCSubgroups.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
