<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<SettingsItems>
  <!-- Kinetic models settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>OralAbsorptionFactor</Id>
    <Name>Default oral absorption factor for non-dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>
      When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, non-dietary oral
      exposures (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>0.1</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>OralAbsorptionFactorForDietaryExposure</Id>
    <Name>Default oral absorption factor for dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>
      When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, dietary exposures
      (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose .
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>1</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DermalAbsorptionFactor</Id>
    <Name>Default dermal absorption factor for non-dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>
      When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, dermal exposures
      (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>0.1</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>InhalationAbsorptionFactor</Id>
    <Name>Default inhalation absorption factor for non-dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>
      When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, inhalation exposures
      (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>0.1</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>InternalModelType</Id>
    <Name>Specify the type of kinetic model</Name>
    <Description>Specify the type of model to convert external exposure to the internal level.</Description>
    <ValueType>InternalModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>KCFSubgroupDependent</Id>
    <Name>Use kinetic conversion factors subgroup</Name>
    <Description>
      Kinetic conversion factors are dependent on subgroups (e.g. based on age or gender, see dataformats KineticConversionfactorsSGs).
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
    <DefaultValue>true</DefaultValue>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ResampleKineticConversionFactors</Id>
    <Name>Resample kinetic conversion factors</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether kinetic conversion factors are resampled.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
