<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TableDefinition>
  <Id>DoseResponseData</Id>
  <Name>Dose response data</Name>
  <Description>
        Single (two-way) table data format for specifying data of dose response experiments (as alternative for the relational format).
        The column headers are dynamic and should be defined in the table DoseResponseExperiments through fields Substances and Responses (and, optionally, Covariates and Time).
        For responses given as aggregated statistics, also SD, CV, N and Uncertainty are specified as [Datatype:Response].
        E.g., 'SD:Y', 'CV:Y', 'N:Y'. Uncertainty upper 95%limits are specified as 'UncertaintyUpper:Y'.
        For each quantal response an additional column 'N:[responsename]'is required with binomial totals (e.g. Mortality = 3, N:Mortality = 10).
      </Description>
  <TechnicalNotes>
    <TechnicalNote>
          Besides the general table-names that are accepted as valid aliases for this table, the experiment id is also accepted as a valid alias of this data.
          E.g., if there is an experiment with id "experimentA", then the table named "experimentA" will be recognized as the table containing the data of this experiment in this single table format.
        </TechnicalNote>
  </TechnicalNotes>
  <Aliases>
    <string>TwoWayDoseResponseData</string>
    <string>DoseResponseDataTwoWay</string>
    <string>DoseResponseData</string>
  </Aliases>
  <HiddenAliases>
    <string>RawDoseResponseData</string>
  </HiddenAliases>
  <ColumnDefinitions>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="false" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="50">
      <Id>idExperiment</Id>
      <Description>Unique identification code of the dose effect experiment.</Description>
      <Aliases>
        <string>idExperiment</string>
        <string>Experiment</string>
        <string>Code</string>
      </Aliases>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="false" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="50" IsDynamic="true">
      <Id>ExperimentalUnit</Id>
      <Name>Experimental unit</Name>
      <Description>
            Experimental unit numbers or identifiers.
            The column name of the experimental unit should be as specified in the dose response experiment record.
          </Description>
      <Aliases>
        <string>ExperimentalUnit</string>
        <string>ExperimentalUnits</string>
        <string>Experimental unit</string>
      </Aliases>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="100" IsDynamic="true">
      <Id>Substances(s)</Id>
      <Name>Substance(s)</Name>
      <Description>
            One or more columns with doses for each substance, in the unit as specified in the dose response experiment table.
            The column name(s) should match the substance codes listed in the comma-separated list of the substances field of the dose response experiment record.
          </Description>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="100" IsDynamic="true">
      <Id>Responses(s)</Id>
      <Name>Response(s)</Name>
      <Description>
            One or more columns with results for each response, in the unit(s) as specified in the dose response experiment table.
            The column name(s) should match the response codes listed in the comma-separated list of the responses field of the dose response experiment record.
          </Description>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="false" FieldType="Numeric" IsDynamic="true">
      <Id>Time</Id>
      <Description>
            The column containing the observed response times.
            The column name (header) should match that of the Time column in the dose response experiment record.
          </Description>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="false" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="100" IsDynamic="true">
      <Id>Covariate(s)</Id>
      <Description>
            The column(s) containing additional properties of the experimental unit.
            The column name (header) should match the codes of the comma-separated covariates list in the dose response experiment record.
          </Description>
    </ColumnDefinition>
  </ColumnDefinitions>
</TableDefinition>