<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<TableDefinition>
  <Id>NonDietaryExposures</Id>
  <Name>Non-dietary exposures</Name>
  <Description>
    This table defines nominal non-dietary exposure values (such as means) for individuals within the
    non-dietary surveys. It can also be used to specify non-dietary exposures for individuals within the food surveys.
    Each exposure comprises a non-dietary survey (source of exposure); a string identifying an individual, which may or may
    not correspond to the ID of an individual in a food survey; a substance; and dermal, oral and inhalation exposure values.
    Exposures are assumed to be external doses.
  </Description>
  <Aliases>
    <string>NonDietaryExposures</string>
    <string>NonDietaryExposure</string>
  </Aliases>
  <HiddenAliases>
    <string>RawNonDietaryExposures</string>
  </HiddenAliases>
  <TargetDataTable>RawNonDietaryExposures</TargetDataTable>
  <ColumnDefinitions>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="50" OrderRank="1">
      <Id>idIndividual</Id>
      <Description>
        Non-dietary individual identification number. This id may
        1) match with the individual ids of the dietary survey (dietary exposures matched to food survey individuals),
        2) not match with the individual ids of the dietary survey (unmatched individuals),
        or contain a default exposure (indicated by idIndividual = 'General') linking the dietary exposures to individuals based on the demographic criteria defined in the non-dietary survey properties table.
      </Description>
      <TechnicalNotes>
        <TechnicalNote>
          For matching to occur, the user will need to tick the option to ‘match specific dietary survey individuals’ in the user-interface.
          The software will then assign non-dietary exposures to the dietary individuals according to the values in this column.
          Any idIndividual values that do not correspond to individuals in the food survey will be ignored, unless a value 'General' is specified.
          Then the individual should meet the demographic criteria as defined in the non-dietary survey properties table.
          If this box is left unticked, the non-dietary exposures will be randomly allocated to the dietary population provided they meet the demographic criteria.
        </TechnicalNote>
        <TechnicalNote>
          For Excel, the cells of this column should be formatted as 'text'.
        </TechnicalNote>
      </TechnicalNotes>
      <Aliases>
        <string>idIndividual</string>
      </Aliases>
      <ForeignKeyTables>
        <string>Individuals</string>
      </ForeignKeyTables>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="50">
      <Id>idNonDietarySurvey</Id>
      <Description>
        The code of the survey (must correspond to values in id column of non-dietary surveys table).
      </Description>
      <Aliases>
        <string>idNonDietarySurvey</string>
      </Aliases>
      <ForeignKeyTables>
        <string>NonDietarySurveys</string>
      </ForeignKeyTables>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="AlphaNumeric" FieldSize="50" OrderRank="2">
      <Id>idCompound</Id>
      <Name>idSubstance</Name>
      <Description>
        The substance code.
      </Description>
      <Aliases>
        <string>idSubstance</string>
        <string>SubstanceId</string>
        <string>SubstanceCode</string>
        <string>Substance</string>
      </Aliases>
      <PreferredAlias>SubstanceCode</PreferredAlias>
      <HiddenAliases>
        <string>idCompound</string>
        <string>CompoundId</string>
        <string>CompoundCode</string>
        <string>Compound</string>
      </HiddenAliases>
      <ForeignKeyTables>
        <string>Compounds</string>
      </ForeignKeyTables>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="Numeric">
      <Id>Dermal</Id>
      <Description>
        The dermal (non-dietary) exposure value.
      </Description>
      <Aliases>
        <string>Dermal</string>
      </Aliases>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="Numeric">
      <Id>Oral</Id>
      <Description>
        The oral (non-dietary) exposure value.
      </Description>
      <Aliases>
        <string>Oral</string>
      </Aliases>
    </ColumnDefinition>
    <ColumnDefinition Required="true" FieldType="Numeric">
      <Id>Inhalation</Id>
      <Description>
        The inhalation (non-dietary) exposure value.
      </Description>
      <Aliases>
        <string>Inhalation</string>
      </Aliases>
    </ColumnDefinition>
  </ColumnDefinitions>
</TableDefinition>
