<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Module>
  <Id>IntraSpeciesFactors</Id>
  <Name>Intra species factors</Name>
  <ActionType>IntraSpeciesFactors</ActionType>
  <ModuleType>DataModule</ModuleType>
  <TableGroup>IntraSpeciesFactors</TableGroup>
  <AllowDefaultData>true</AllowDefaultData>
  <IsAdvancedActionType>true</IsAdvancedActionType>
  <Description>
    Intra-species factors describe variation between individuals concerning their individual sensitivities to experience well-defined health effects.
    Traditionally the intraspecies factor is a fixed value, but the true distribution might be (very) uncertain. There is some support for
    assuming a lognormal distribution to describe the variability between individuals. In MCRA, intraspecies factors are sampled from a lognormal
    distribution, characterised by a geometric mean (GM) equal to 1 and a geometric standard deviation (GSD) thats needs to be given a value
    representing the intraspecies variability. GM is 1 by definition (50% of the population is assumed to be less sensitive than the average,
    50% is mor sensitive) and has no uncertainty. On the other hand, there is uncertainty about the GSD. In MCRA it is assumed that this uncertainty
    is described by a Chi-square distribution with df degrees of freedom. By specifying a lower and upper bound for the p95 sensitive individual
    e.g. a lower value 2 and upper value 10 (meaning, the p95 individuals are between 2 and 10 times more sensible than the average human), a Chi-square
    distribution can be estimated where 1) the GSD specifies the variability and 2) the degrees of freedom specifies the uncertainty around the GSD.
  </Description>
  <ShortDescription>
    Intra-species factors specify how to convert a hazard characterisation from the average to a sensitive human individual.
  </ShortDescription>
  <DataDescription>
    In the simplest approach, intra-species factors are fixed factors.
    In a higher tier, lower and upper values for the intra-species factor are used to derive a variability distribution (log-normal around 1) and an uncertainty distribution for the geometric standard deviation related to human variability in sensitivity.
  </DataDescription>
  <Entities>
    <Entity>Substances</Entity>
    <Entity>Effects</Entity>
  </Entities>
  <SelectionInputs>
    <Input>ActiveSubstances</Input>
  </SelectionInputs>
  <UncertaintySettings>
    <UncertaintySetting>ResampleIntraSpecies</UncertaintySetting>
  </UncertaintySettings>
  <SelectionSettings>
    <SelectionSetting>DefaultIntraSpeciesFactor</SelectionSetting>
    <SelectionSetting source="ActiveSubstances">FilterByAvailableHazardCharacterisation</SelectionSetting>
  </SelectionSettings>
  <CalculationSettings>
    <CalculationSetting source="Substances">MultipleSubstances</CalculationSetting>
  </CalculationSettings>
  <UncertaintySources>
    <UncertaintySource>IntraSpecies</UncertaintySource>
  </UncertaintySources>
</Module>
