<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<UnitDefinition>
  <Id>ConcentrationModelType</Id>
  <Name>Concentration model types</Name>
  <Description>
    Accepted Concentration model types. Controlled terminology.
  </Description>
  <Units>
    <Unit>
      <Id>Empirical</Id>
      <Name>Empirical</Name>
      <ShortName>Empirical</ShortName>
      <Description>
        Residues are sampled from the empirical distribution. Fallback: zero.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
    <Unit>
      <Id>NonDetectSpikeLogNormal</Id>
      <Name>Censored value Spike LogNormal</Name>
      <ShortName>CVSpike-LogN</ShortName>
      <Description>
        A lognormal model (logarithmic transformed values, with parameters mu and sigma^2) is fitted to the positive residues values. LOR information is not used. Fallback (if number of positives less than 2): Empirical, but Maximum Residu Limit for pessimistic assessments.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
    <Unit>
      <Id>NonDetectSpikeTruncatedLogNormal</Id>
      <Name>Censored Spike Truncated LogNormal</Name>
      <ShortName>CVSpike-TruncLogN</ShortName>
      <Description>
        A truncated lognormal model (with parameters mu and sigma^2) is fitted to the positive residues values. The LOR is used to estimate the truncated left tail of the distribution. Fallback: Lognormal non-detect spike.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
    <Unit>
      <Id>CensoredLogNormal</Id>
      <Name>Censored LogNormal</Name>
      <ShortName>CensLogN</ShortName>
      <Description>
        Advanced. A censored lognormal model (with parameters mu and sigma^2) is fitted to the censored and positives residue values. Note, this model is not available when agricultural use information is used. Fallback: Lognormal non-detect spike.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
    <Unit>
      <Id>ZeroSpikeCensoredLogNormal</Id>
      <Name>Zero Spike Censored LogNormal</Name>
      <ShortName>ZeroSpike-CensLogN</ShortName>
      <Description>
        Advanced. A mixture model with zero spike (p0) and censored lognormal model (with parameters mu and sigma^2) is fitted to the censored and positives residue values. Note, this model is not available when agricultural use information is used. Fallback: Censored lognormal.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
    <Unit>
      <Id>MaximumResidueLimit</Id>
      <Name>Censored Spike Maximum Residue Limit</Name>
      <ShortName>CVSpike-MRL</ShortName>
      <Description>
        Censored Spike Maximum Residue Limit.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
    <Unit>
      <Id>SummaryStatistics</Id>
      <Name>Summary statistics</Name>
      <ShortName>Summary statistic</ShortName>
      <Description>
        Summary statistics.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
    <Unit>
      <Id>LogNormal</Id>
      <Name>LogNormal</Name>
      <ShortName>LogN</ShortName>
      <Description>
        Lognormal model.
      </Description>
    </Unit>
  </Units>
</UnitDefinition>
