<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<SettingsItems>

  <!--Agricultural use settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>OccurrencePatternsTier</Id>
    <Name>Occurrence patterns tier</Name>
    <Description>Specifies the occurrence patterns should should be treated/modelled according to a pre-defined tier or custom.</Description>
    <ValueType>OccurrencePatternsTier</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseOccurrenceFrequencies</Id>
    <Name>Use occurrence frequencies</Name>
    <Description>Account for occurrence frequencies for combinations of food and substance in the exposure calculations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseOccurrencePatternsForResidueGeneration</Id>
    <Name>Use occurrence patterns for generating simulated samples</Name>
    <Description>When selected, this simulated samples will be based on occurrence patterns.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAgriculturalUseTable</Id>
    <Name>Use occurrence frequencies for imputation</Name>
    <Description>
      Use of occurrence frequencies (e.g., agricultural use frequencies) is relevant for imputation of censored values in the concentration data.
      Part of the observed censored values and missing values may be imputed with zero when the occurrence frequency is smaller than 100%.
      If checked, occurrence frequencies are expected as input of this action, otherwise 100% potential presence is assumed for all substances on all foods.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SetMissingAgriculturalUseAsUnauthorized</Id>
    <Name>Associate the unspecified percentage with no-occurrence for foods with at least one specified occurrence pattern</Name>
    <Description>
      If checked, for foods with at least one specified occurrence pattern, unspecified occurrence patterns for the same food are assumed to be associated with no use.
      If unchecked, all substances are considered to be authorised (potentially present in samples).
      Note that this setting cannot be used for foods that have no specified AUs. These foods have 100% potential presence of all substances.
      To declare all AUs on such a food un-authorised, include an empty AU with percentage 100% in the AU data table
      (i.e., use an AU for this food, without specifying substances in the AU Substances table)
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAgriculturalUsePercentage</Id>
    <Name>Apply occurrence pattern percentages</Name>
    <Description>If checked, use the percentages of potential presence as specified by the occurrence patterns. If unchecked, 100% potential presence in samples is assumed for all substances identified by the occurrence patterns.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ScaleUpOccurencePatterns</Id>
    <Name>Scale up use frequency to 100%</Name>
    <Description>Scale up use frequency to 100%.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictOccurencePatternScalingToAuthorisedUses</Id>
    <Name>Restrict use percentage up-scaling to authorised uses</Name>
    <Description>Restrict use percentage up-scaling to authorised uses.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!--Assessment settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureType</Id>
    <Name>Risk type</Name>
    <Description>The type of exposure considered in the assessment; acute (short term) or chronic (long-term).</Description>
    <ValueType>ExposureType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MultipleSubstances</Id>
    <Name>Multiple substances analysis</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the assessment involves multiple substances.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MultipleSubstanceHandlingMethod</Id>
    <Name>Treatment of multiple substances</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether results should be cumulated in a single assessment or if multiple assessments should be run, for substance independently.    </Description>
    <ValueType>MultipleSubstanceHandlingMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Cumulative</Id>
    <Name>Express results in terms of reference substance equivalents (cumulative)</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the assessment involves multiple substances and results should be cumulated over all substances.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Aggregate</Id>
    <Name>Include dietary and non-dietary routes of exposure</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the assessment involves both dietary and non-dietary (oral, inhalatory or dermal) routes of exposure.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MultipleHealthEffects</Id>
    <Name>Multiple health effects</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the assessment involves multiple health effects.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TotalDietStudy</Id>
    <Name>Total diet study concentration data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether exposure is based on sampling data from total diet studies.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseMonitoringDataForTDS</Id>
    <Name>Use monitoring data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether monitoring data are used in addition to total diet study data.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!--Amount model settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Covariable</Id>
    <Name>Covariable</Name>
    <Description>Covariates are continuous variables with an unlimited set of levels e.g. age.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Covariate</Id>
    <Name>Covariate</Name>
    <Description>Cofactors are qualitative variables with a limited set of levels e.g. gender.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CovariateModelType</Id>
    <Name>Amount model covariate model</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether, and how to model exposures amounts as function of covariates.</Description>
    <ValueType>CovariateModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FunctionType</Id>
    <Name>Function</Name>
    <Description>Functional relation between exposure and covariable.</Description>
    <ValueType>FunctionType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TestingLevel</Id>
    <Name>Testing level</Name>
    <Description>Significance level for testing the degree of the function. e.g., 0.05.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TestingMethod</Id>
    <Name>Testing method</Name>
    <Description>Starting from a full model (backward) or empty model (forward).</Description>
    <ValueType>TestingMethodType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MinDegreesOfFreedom</Id>
    <Name>Minimum degrees of freedom</Name>
    <Description>Order of function. Determines the minimum degree of complexity of the function.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MaxDegreesOfFreedom</Id>
    <Name>Maximum degrees of freedom</Name>
    <Description>Order of function. Determines the maximum degree of complexity of the function.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!--Active substances settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterByAvailableHazardDose</Id>
    <Name>Restrict active substances to substances with available PODs</Name>
    <Description>Restrict assessment group membership based on presence/absence of points of departure.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterByAvailableHazardCharacterisation</Id>
    <Name>Restrict active substances to substances with available hazard characterisations</Name>
    <Description>Restrict assessment group membership based on presence/absence of hazard characterisations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseHazardCharacterisationsToDetermineActiveSubstances</Id>
    <Name>Use hazard characterisations to determine active substances</Name>
    <Description>Use hazard characterisations to determine active substances.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseQsarModels</Id>
    <Name>Derive memberships from QSAR membership data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether QSAR membership data is used for computing the assessment group memberships.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseMolecularDockingModels</Id>
    <Name>Derive memberships from molecular docking data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether molecular docking data is used for computing the assessment group memberhips.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseProbabilisticMemberships</Id>
    <Name>Use probabilistic assessment group memberships</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether substance memberships should be expressed in terms of probabilities (probabilistic). Otherwise, substance memberships are expressed as in or out (crisp).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>AssessmentGroupMembershipCalculationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Membership calculation method</Name>
    <Description>Calculation method for computing assessment group memberships: majority/any (crisp methods), ratio/Bayesian (probabilistic methods)</Description>
    <ValueType>AssessmentGroupMembershipCalculationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IncludeSubstancesWithUnknowMemberships</Id>
    <Name>Include substances without membership information</Name>
    <Description>For non-probabilistic methods: specifies whether substances for which no membership information is available in the specified inputs should be included in the assessment group.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>PriorMembershipProbability</Id>
    <Name>Default/prior membership probability</Name>
    <Description>Default substance membership probability for which no membership information is available in the specified inputs. Prior probability for Bayesian method.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!--Concentration model settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConcentrationModelChoice</Id>
    <Name>Concentration model tier</Name>
    <Description>Custom model, or set according to EFSA Guidance 2012. Note: you may need to set the tier separately in sub-modules.</Description>
    <ValueType>ConcentrationModelChoice</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DefaultConcentrationModel</Id>
    <Name>Default concentration model</Name>
    <Description>
      The concentration model type that will be used as default for all food/substance combinations.
      If this model type cannot be fitted, e.g., due to a lack of data, a simpler model will be chosen automatically as a fall-back.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>ConcentrationModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsFallbackMrl</Id>
    <Name>Include MRL fallback model</Name>
    <Description>Use the MRL as fallback model in case the occurrence data is insufficient for other concentration modelling options.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FractionOfMrl</Id>
    <Name>MRL Factor (f x MRL)</Name>
    <Description>Use f x MRL as concentration estimate of the MRL models.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NonDetectsHandlingMethod</Id>
    <Name>Censored values replacement</Name>
    <Description>How to replace censored values (when not co-modelled, as in censored models).</Description>
    <ValueType>NonDetectsHandlingMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FractionOfLOR</Id>
    <Name>Factor f (f x LOR or f x LOD or LOD + f x (LOQ - LOD)</Name>
    <Description>Replace censored values by Limit of reporting (LOR), Non-detects (LOD) or Non-quantifications (LOQ) times this factor. Constant (f), e.g. 0.5.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictLorImputationToAuthorisedUses</Id>
    <Name>Restrict LOR imputation to authorised uses</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether imputation of factor x LOR should be limited to authorised uses only.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsProcessing</Id>
    <Name>Apply processing factors</Name>
    <Description>Specified in table ProcessingFactor. If checked, processing factors are applied. Concentrations in the consumed food may be different from concentrations in the modelled food in monitoring programs (typically raw food) due to processing, such as peeling, washing, cooking etc. If unchecked, no processing information is used. This is in most (though not all) cases a worst-case assumption</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsSampleBased</Id>
    <Name>Sample based</Name>
    <Description>Include co-occurrence of substances in samples in simulations. If checked, substance residue concentrations are sampled using the correlations between values on the same sample. If unchecked, any correlation between substances is ignored, substance residue concentrations are sampled ignoring the correlations between values on the same sample.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImputeMissingValues</Id>
    <Name>Impute missing values from available values (if unchecked, missing values are imputed with 0)</Name>
    <Description>If checked, in procedure of EFSA Guidance 2012, Appendix 1, impute missing values using substance based concentration models. If unchecked, missing values are imputed by 0.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CorrelateImputedValueWithSamplePotency</Id>
    <Name>Correlate imputed values with sample potency</Name>
    <Description>If checked, in procedure of EFSA Guidance 2012, Appendix 1, correlate high imputed values with high cumulative potency samples. If unchecked, random imputation.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsSingleSamplePerDay</Id>
    <Name>Consumptions on the same day come from the same sample</Name>
    <Description>if checked, in procedure of EFSA Guidance 2012, section 4.1.1, all consumptions of a raw commodity of an individual on the same day are assumed to come from the same sample. If unchecked, all consumptions of a raw commodity of an individual on the same day are assumed to come from different samples.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsCorrelation</Id>
    <Name>Maximise co-occurrence of high values in simulated samples</Name>
    <Description>Within each pattern of substance presence. If checked, substance residue concentrations are sorted within co-occurrence patterns of substances on the same samples. After sorting, high residue values occur more frequently on the same sample. This choice is conservative. If unchecked, substance residue concentrations are sampled at random, ignoring any co-occurrence patterns of substances on the same samples. This choice is less conservative.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConcentrationModelTypesPerFoodCompound</Id>
    <Name>ConcentrationModelTypesPerFoodCompound</Name>
    <Description>Concentration model types per food substance</Description>
    <ValueType>ConcentrationModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Concentrations settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConcentrationsTier</Id>
    <Name>Concentrations tier</Name>
    <Description>Specifies the concentration data should be treated according to a pre-defined tier or custom.</Description>
    <ValueType>ConcentrationsTier</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseComplexResidueDefinitions</Id>
    <Name>Use substance conversion rules</Name>
    <Description>If checked, concentrations are modelled in terms of active substances (using substance conversion).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseDeterministicConversionFactors</Id>
    <Name>Use substance conversion factors</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether to use substance conversion factors to convert measured substance concentrations to active substance concentrations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterConcentrationLimitExceedingSamples</Id>
    <Name>Filter samples exceeding the concentration limits</Name>
    <Description>If checked, samples with at least one substance concentration higher than some factor (concentration limit filter exceedance factor) times the MRL are filtered out.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConcentrationLimitFilterFractionExceedanceThreshold</Id>
    <Name>Concentration limit filter exceedance factor</Name>
    <Description>The multiplication factor for the concentration limit exceedance filter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SubstanceTranslationAllocationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Substance conversion method</Name>
    <Description>Allocation method for assigning active substance concentrations from measured substance concentrations based on substance translations.</Description>
    <ValueType>SubstanceTranslationAllocationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConsiderAuthorisationsForSubstanceConversion</Id>
    <Name>Account for substance authorisations in substance conversions</Name>
    <Description>Account for substance authorisations when allocating measured substances to active substance using substance conversions.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RetainAllAllocatedSubstancesAfterAllocation</Id>
    <Name>Retain all allocated substances after active substance allocation</Name>
    <Description>If checked, all allocated substances kept after substance conversion. Otherwise, the concentration data is restricted to the active substances of the assessment group.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TryFixDuplicateAllocationInconsistencies</Id>
    <Name>Fix duplicate substance allocation inconsistencies</Name>
    <Description>Resolve inconsistencies when active substance allocation leads to multiple concentration value estimates for the same active substance. This method uses the mean of the positives or zero concentrations when available, or else the lowest of the censored values.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExtrapolateConcentrations</Id>
    <Name>Use extrapolation rules</Name>
    <Description>Use extrapolation rules to extrapolate food samples for foods with a limited amount of samples (data poor foods) from other foods (data rich foods).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ThresholdForExtrapolation</Id>
    <Name>Threshold for extrapolation</Name>
    <Description>Threshold for extrapolation.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConsiderMrlForExtrapolations</Id>
    <Name>Restrict extrapolations to equal MRLs</Name>
    <Description>Restrict extrapolations to equal MRLs.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConsiderAuthorisationsForExtrapolations</Id>
    <Name>Restrict extrapolations to authorised uses</Name>
    <Description>Only extrapolate if substance use is authorised.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImputeWaterConcentrations</Id>
    <Name>Impute water concentrations</Name>
    <Description>Impute constant concentration values on the selected (water) commodity.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeWater</Id>
    <Name>Water commodity</Name>
    <Description>The commodity for which constant concentration values should be added.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>WaterConcentrationValue</Id>
    <Name>Water concentration value (µg/kg)</Name>
    <Description>Constant concentration value that should be used for water (in µg/kg).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictWaterImputationToMostPotentSubstances</Id>
    <Name>Restrict water imputation to the five most toxic substances</Name>
    <Description>Restrict water imputation to the five most toxic substances.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictWaterImputationToAuthorisedUses</Id>
    <Name>Restrict water imputation to authorised uses</Name>
    <Description>Restrict water imputation to authorised uses.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalCommodity</Id>
    <Name>Include focal commodity concentrations</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether there is monitoring data that should replace part of the consumption data for the specified focal commodities.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalCommodityReplacementMethod</Id>
    <Name>Focal commodity concentrations replacement method</Name>
    <Description>Replacement method to be used for replacing base concentration data with concentration data of the focal commodity/commodities concentrations.</Description>
    <ValueType>FocalCommodityReplacementMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalCommodityScenarioOccurrencePercentage</Id>
    <Name>Focal commodity substance occurrence percentage</Name>
    <Description>Anticipated occurrence percentage / agricultural use percentage of the focal commodity.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalCommodityConcentrationAdjustmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Adjustment factor for the focal food/substance concentration</Name>
    <Description>Optional adjustment factor for the focal food/substance concentration. E.g., the expected ratio of mean monitoring concentration and mean field trial concentration.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseDeterministicSubstanceConversionsForFocalCommodity</Id>
    <Name>Use deterministic substance conversions for focal commodity</Name>
    <Description>Convert measured substance concentrations of focal commodity to active substance concentrations using deterministic substance conversion factors.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalFoods</Id>
    <Name>Focal commodity foods</Name>
    <Description>The foods for which background concentration data are to be replaced by focal commodity concentrations.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalSubstances</Id>
    <Name>Focal commodity substances</Name>
    <Description>The substances for which background concentration data are to be replaced by focal commodity concentrations.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterSamplesByYear</Id>
    <Name>Filter samples by year</Name>
    <Description>If checked, samples are filtered based on the selected years.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
     <Id>AlignSampleDateSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
	 <Name>Align sample date subset with population</Name>
	 <Description>If checked, the samples are filtered based on the period of the selected population.</Description>
	 <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
     <Id>AlignSampleSeasonSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
	 <Name>Align sampling month subset with population</Name>
	 <Description>If checked, the samples are filtered based on the month/period of the selected population.</Description>
	 <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
     <Id>AlignSampleLocationSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
	 <Name>Align sampling location subset with population</Name>
	 <Description>If checked, the samples are filtered based on the location of the selected population.</Description>
	 <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
     <Id>AlignSampleRegionSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
	 <Name>Align sampling region subset with population</Name>
	 <Description>If checked, the samples are filtered based on the region of the selected population.</Description>
	 <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterSamplesByMonth</Id>
    <Name>Filter samples by month</Name>
    <Description>If checked, samples are filtered based on the specified sampling month.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterSamplesByLocation</Id>
    <Name>Filter samples by location</Name>
    <Description>If checked, samples are filtered based on the selected locations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterSamplesByRegion</Id>
    <Name>Filter samples by region</Name>
    <Description>If checked, samples are filtered based on the selected regions.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterSamplesByProductionMethod</Id>
    <Name>Filter samples by production method</Name>
    <Description>If checked, samples are filtered based on the selected production methods.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IncludeMissingDateValueRecords</Id>
    <Name>Include samples with unspecified sampling date</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then samples for which the sample date is not specified are also included by the sample date filter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IncludeMissingLocationRecords</Id>
    <Name>Include samples with unspecified location</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then samples for which the sample location is not specified are also included by the sample location filter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IncludeMissingRegionRecords</Id>
    <Name>Include samples with unspecified region</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then samples for which the sample region is not specified are also included by the sample region filter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IncludeMissingProductionMethodRecords</Id>
    <Name>Include samples with unspecified production method</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then samples for which the sample production method is not specified are also included by the sample production method filter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <!--In fact these SettingsItems are empty, only used for Name and Description-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SampleYears</Id>
    <Name>Sample years</Name>
    <Description>The years for which samples are filtered.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SampleMonths</Id>
    <Name>Sample months</Name>
    <Description>The months for which samples are filtered.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SampleLocations</Id>
    <Name>Sample locations</Name>
    <Description>The locations for which samples are filtered.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SampleRegions</Id>
    <Name>Sample regions</Name>
    <Description>The regions for which samples are filtered.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SampleProductionMethods</Id>
    <Name>Sample production methods</Name>
    <Description>The production methods for which samples are filtered.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Scenario analysis -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseScenario</Id>
    <Name>Apply reduction-to-limit scenario</Name>
    <Description>
      Total diet study: specify reduction-to-limit scenario. If unchecked, all residue values are taken as such (base scenario: apply
      no reduction factors). If checked, reduction factors are applied for selected foods. Select foods where a reduction is assumed (only foods
      with Percentile > Limit are shown). Only foods with reduction factors > 1 (percentile / limit) are shown.
    </Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsMrlSettingScenario</Id>
    <Name>Apply MRL setting scenario</Name>
    <Description>
      Use this option to test the scenario for using, for a substance and a selected set of foods, a specific MRL and assuming that the residue concentrations are drawn according to f x MRL.
    </Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ProposedMrl</Id>
    <Name>Proposed MRL (mg/kg)</Name>
    <Description>
      The proposed MRL in (mg/kg) for the selected foods and substance.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <!--In fact these SettingsItems are empty, only used for Name and Description-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ScenarioAnalysisFoods</Id>
    <Name>Scenario analysis foods</Name>
    <Description>
      The foods of interest for the scenario analysis.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ScenarioAnalysisSubstance</Id>
    <Name>Scenario analysis substance</Name>
    <Description>
      The substance for the MRL setting scenario analysis.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Food survey -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeFoodSurvey</Id>
    <Name>Food survey</Name>
    <Description>The food consumption survey representative for the population of interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>LoopMultipleSurveys</Id>
    <Name>Loop over multiple surveys</Name>
    <Description>Loop over the selected surveys.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Food conversion settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseProcessing</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using processing info</Name>
    <Description>
      Warning, the processing step is deprecated and is currently only maintained for backwards compatibility reasons. See documentation for more details how processed foods are converted in the upgraded conversion algorithm.
      Step 2a: try to find the code in the processing table. Try to find the code in the FoodTranslation table (step 3a) to account for weight reduction/increase (translation proportion).
      If unchecked (default), processing table is ignored. If successful, restart at step 1.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseComposition</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using food translations</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 3a: try to find food translations for the current food (i.e., the ingredients of a composite food). This may result in one or more food codes for ingredients, and the iterative algorithm will proceed with each of the ingredient food codes in turn.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseTdsComposition</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using TDS food sample compositions</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 3b: try to find the code in the TDS food sample compositions table (idFood), a default translation proportion of 100% is assumed. The iterative algorithm will proceed with a TDS food (column idTDSFood) sample.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseReadAcrossFoodTranslations</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using food extrapolations</Name>
    <Description>Step 3c: try to find read across codes. If unchecked, read across table is ignored, default is 'Use read across info'. E.g. for pineapple no measurements are found but by specifying that pineapple is converted to FruitMix (with a default proportion of 100%), the TDS sample concentration value of FruitMix will be used for pineapple (as-eaten or as ingredient). If successful, restart at step 1.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseMarketShares</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using market shares</Name>
    <Description>Step 4: try to find subtype codes, e.g. 'xxx$*' in the market shares table.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseSubTypes</Id>
    <Name>Allow marketshares not summing to 100%</Name>
    <Description>Specify whether to rescale market share percentages that do not sum to 100%. If checked, then foods with marketshares not summing to 100% are allowed. If not, then these foods are ignored in the analysis.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseSuperTypes</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion to supertypes</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 5: try to find supertypes, e.g. 'xxx$yyy' is converted to 'xxx' (optional, check box if you want to use this). If checked, allows for linkage of consumed foods coded at a lower hierarchical level to foods with measured concentrations at a higher hierarchical level e.g. consumed is Apple (code PF$Apple) --&gt; measured is Pome Fruit (code PF). Note: food codes are split on '$'. Measurements of substances on food are available at a less detailed food coding level than consumption data. MCRA allows to use the concentration data of a supertype for all underlying food codes. If successful, restart at step 1.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseDefaultProcessingFactor</Id>
    <Name>Allow conversion using default processing factors</Name>
    <Description>
      Step 6: remove processing part. If unchecked, no default processing factors are assumed, default is 'Use default processing factors'. If successful, restart at step 1.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SubstanceIndependent</Id>
    <Name>Conversion is substance independent</Name>
    <Description>Conversion of foods is independent of the substance.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Modelled foods selection settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DeriveModelledFoodsFromSampleBasedConcentrations</Id>
    <Name>Derive modelled foods from concentrations</Name>
    <Description>Derive modelled foods from sample based concentration data.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DeriveModelledFoodsFromSingleValueConcentrations</Id>
    <Name>Derive modelled foods from single value concentrations</Name>
    <Description>Derive modelled foods from single value concentrations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseWorstCaseValues</Id>
    <Name>Derive modelled foods from concentration limits</Name>
    <Description>Derive modelled foods from concentration limits.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FoodIncludeNonDetects</Id>
    <Name>If checked, include foods with only censored value measurements</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether foods with only censored value measurements are part of the exposure assessment (default yes).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CompoundIncludeNonDetects</Id>
    <Name>If checked, include substances with only censored value measurements</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether substances with only censored value measurements are part of the exposure assessment (default yes).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CompoundIncludeNoMeasurements</Id>
    <Name>If checked, include substances without measurements</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether substances without any measurements should be included.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Food selection settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodesHumanMonitoringSurveys</Id>
    <Name>Survey</Name>
    <Description>The survey that should be included in the action.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodesHumanMonitoringSamplingMethods</Id>
    <Name>Sampling method</Name>
    <Description>The sampling method that should be included in the action.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HumanMonitoringNonDetectsHandlingMethod</Id>
    <Name>Censored values handling method</Name>
    <Description>Method for dealing with censored value samples in human monitoring data.</Description>
    <ValueType>NonDetectsHandlingMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HumanMonitoringFractionOfLor</Id>
    <Name>Fraction for censored value replacement</Name>
    <Description>Factor used for replacing the censored value.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MissingValueImputationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Missing value imputation method</Name>
    <Description>Imputation method for missing values.</Description>
    <ValueType>MissingValueImputationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  
  <!-- Biological matrix concentration comparisons settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CorrelateTargetConcentrations</Id>
    <Name>Correlate monitoring with modelled concentrations</Name>
    <Description>Correlate monitoring with modelled concentrations. This is option prevents that monitoring and modelled individuals that are coded unintentionally with identical id's or codes are correlated.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Consumption selection settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConsumerDaysOnly</Id>
    <Name>Restrict population to consumers or consumer days only</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the population should be restricted to the individuals (chronic) or individual days (acute) that have non-zero consumption.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictPopulationByFoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Restrict population to consumers or consumer days with consumptions of specific foods</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the population should be restricted to the individuals (chronic) or individual days (acute) consuming any of the foods of the specified subset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalFoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Selected foods-as-eaten</Name>
    <Description>Set of consumed foods that are of particular interest for restricting the consumers / consumption days.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictConsumptionsByFoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Consumption subset: restrict to consumptions of specific foods</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then the consumptions are restricted to those of the specified food-as-eaten subset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IncludeMissingIndividualDayRecords</Id>
    <Name>Include individual day records with missing dates</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then individual day records with missing dates are included in the individual day subset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FoodAsEatenSubset</Id>
    <Name>Selected foods-as-eaten</Name>
    <Description>Set of consumed foods that are of particular interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsDefaultSamplingWeight</Id>
    <Name>Ignore sampling weights</Name>
    <Description>If checked, individual sampling weights are not used (sampling weight = 1). If unchecked, the specified sampling weights are used.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseHbmSamplingWeights</Id>
    <Name>Use sampling weights</Name>
    <Description>If checked, individual sampling weights are used. If unchecked, the individual sampling weights are not in the calculations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsPerPerson</Id>
    <Name>Report consumptions and exposures per individual instead of per kg body weight</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether body weights should be ignored and consumptions and exposures should be expressed per individual. Otherwise, the consumptions and exposures are per kg body weight.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseBodyWeightStandardisedConsumptionDistribution</Id>
    <Name>Use standardised consumption distributions before calculation of single values</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether single values are calculated on individual consumptions standardised with body weight and then multiplied by the mean body weight. Otherwise, single values are calculated on the original consumptions (per day). Note that both methods lead to different estimates for the single value.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExcludeIndividualsWithLessThanNDays</Id>
    <Name>Exclude individuals with less than N days</Name>
    <Description>Filter out all individuals with less than N survey days.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MinimumNumberOfDays</Id>
    <Name>N (number of days in survey)</Name>
    <Description>Specify the nominal number of days in the survey to filter out all individuals with less than N survey days.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MatchIndividualSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
    <Name>Match consumer selection to population definition options</Name>
    <Description>Match consumption data to population definition. Use population definitions (default), ignore all population definitions or use a selection of properties.</Description>
    <ValueType>IndividualSubsetType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MatchHbmIndividualSubsetWithPopulation</Id>
    <Name>Match HBM individuals selection to population definition options</Name>
    <Description>Match HBM individuals selection to population definition. Use population definitions (default), ignore all population definitions or use a selection of properties.</Description>
    <ValueType>IndividualSubsetType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Consumers and focal-food consumers subset settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ModelledFoodsConsumerDaysOnly</Id>
    <Name>Restrict population to consumers or consumer days only (food-as-measured)</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the population should be restricted to the individuals (chronic) or individual days (acute) with consumptions containing any of the modelled foods.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictPopulationByModelledFoodSubset</Id>
    <Name>Restrict population to consumers or consumer days with consumptions of specified modelled foods only</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the population should be restricted to the individuals (chronic) or individual days (acute) with consumptions containing any of the specified modelled food subset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FocalFoodAsMeasuredSubset</Id>
    <Name>Selected modelled foods</Name>
    <Description>Set of consumed modelled foods that are of particular interest for restricting the consumers / consumption days.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Modelled foods subset settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictToModelledFoodSubset</Id>
    <Name>Restrict to specific modelled foods (modelled foods subset)</Name>
    <Description>If checked, then the assessment is restricted to the specified modelled foods.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ModelledFoodSubset</Id>
    <Name>Selected modelled foods</Name>
    <Description>Set of modelled foods that are of particular interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Population definition settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>PopulationSubsetSelection</Id>
    <Name>Define populations based on specified individual properties</Name>
    <Description>Define a population by selecting specific ranges/values of individual properties. E.g., the female population between ages 18 and 45 is composed of the properties gender (female) and age (between 18 and 45).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsPopulationSubsetByGender</Id>
    <Name>Match individuals by gender</Name>
    <Description>Match the population by gender.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsPopulationSubsetByAge</Id>
    <Name>Match individuals by age</Name>
    <Description>Match the population by age.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>GenderSubsetSelection</Id>
    <Name>Gender</Name>
    <Description>Match the population by selected gender.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MinimumAgeSubsetSelection</Id>
    <Name>Minimum age</Name>
    <Description>Match the population to individuals with at least this age.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MaximumAgeSubsetSelection</Id>
    <Name>Maximum Age</Name>
    <Description>Match the population to individuals with at most the specified age.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>LoopMultiplePopulations</Id>
    <Name>Loop over multiple populations</Name>
    <Description>Loop over the selected populations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SelectedFoodSurveySubsetProperties</Id>
    <Name>Select one or more individual(day) properties to filter the population</Name>
    <Description>Select one or more individual(day) properties to filter the individuals(days) in the population.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SelectedHbmSurveySubsetProperties</Id>
    <Name>Select one or more individual(day) properties to filter the population</Name>
    <Description>Select one or more individual(day) properties to filter the individuals(days) in the population.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NominalPopulationBodyWeight</Id>
    <Name>Nominal population bodyweight (kg)</Name>
    <Description>Nominal population bodyweight in kg (needed for single value calculations).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Individual day subset selection -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterIndividualDaysByMonth</Id>
    <Name>Include month in population definition</Name>
    <Description>Individual days are filtered based on the specified sampling month.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IndividualDayMonths</Id>
    <Name>Individual day months</Name>
    <Description>Set of months for which individual days are filtered.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Sample subset selection settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SampleSubsetSelection</Id>
    <Name>Filter samples by specific property values (subset selection)</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether a subset selection on specific sample properties should be made (e.g., by country or by year).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Frequency model settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FrequencyModelCovariateModelType</Id>
    <Name>Frequency model covariates model</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether, and how to model exposure frequency as function of covariates.</Description>
    <ValueType>CovariateModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FrequencyModelFunctionType</Id>
    <Name>Function</Name>
    <Description>Functional relation between exposure and covariable.</Description>
    <ValueType>FunctionType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FrequencyModelTestingLevel</Id>
    <Name>Testing level</Name>
    <Description>Significance level for testing the degree of the function. e.g., 0.05.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FrequencyModelTestingMethod</Id>
    <Name>Testing method</Name>
    <Description>Starting from a full model (backward) or empty model (forward).</Description>
    <ValueType>TestingMethodType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FrequencyModelMinDegreesOfFreedom</Id>
    <Name>Minimum degrees of freedom</Name>
    <Description>Order of function. Determines the minimum degree of complexity of the function.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FrequencyModelMaxDegreesOfFreedom</Id>
    <Name>Maximum degrees of freedom</Name>
    <Description>Order of function. Determines the maximum degree of complexity of the function.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Dose response data settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodesExperiments</Id>
    <Name>Experiments</Name>
    <Description>The dose response experiments of interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MergeDoseResponseExperimentsData</Id>
    <Name>Merge dose response data of multiple experiments</Name>
    <Description>
      Specifies whether the dose response data of multiple experiments should be merged into one large dose response data set.
    </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Effect model settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HealthEffectType</Id>
    <Name>Health effect type</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the health effect is a risk (negative) or benefit (positive).</Description>
    <ValueType>HealthEffectType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RiskMetricType</Id>
    <Name>Risk metric type</Name>
    <Description>Report risks in terms of hazard index (HI = 1/MOE) or margin of exposure.</Description>
    <ValueType>RiskMetricType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>LeftMargin</Id>
    <Name>Left margin safety plot</Name>
    <Description>Left margin of the plot for margins of exposure or hazard indices.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RightMargin</Id>
    <Name>Right margin safety plot</Name>
    <Description>Right margin of the plot for margins of exposure of hazard indices.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfLabels</Id>
    <Name>Number of plot labels</Name>
    <Description>Maximum number of labels to plot in hazard vs exposure plot.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsEAD</Id>
    <Name>Show equivalent animal dose output</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether equivalent animal doses should be reported in the output.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ThresholdMarginOfExposure</Id>
    <Name>Threshold safety plot</Name>
    <Description>Threshold for interpretation in the margin of exposure or hazard index plot, e.g. MOE = HI = 1 or MOE = 100 and HI = 0.01.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ConfidenceInterval</Id>
    <Name>Inclusion percentage variability interval</Name>
    <Description>The central percentage of the variability distribution to include in intervals for exposure, hazard and MOE (e.g. 90 means p5-p95).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DefaultInterSpeciesFactorGeometricMean</Id>
    <Name>Interspecies factor geometric mean</Name>
    <Description>Interspecies factor geometric mean.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DefaultInterSpeciesFactorGeometricStandardDeviation</Id>
    <Name>Interspecies factor geometric standard deviation</Name>
    <Description>Interspecies factor geometric standard deviation.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DefaultIntraSpeciesFactor</Id>
    <Name>Intra-species factor</Name>
    <Description>Intra-species factor.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfSubstances</Id>
    <Name>Number of substances in hazard vs. exposure plot</Name>
    <Description>Maximum number of substances to plot in hazard vs exposure plot.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <!--Single value risk settings-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SingleValueRiskCalculationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Single value risk calculation method</Name>
    <Description>Calculate single value from  exposures and hazard or from an individual risks distribution.</Description>
    <ValueType>SingleValueRiskCalculationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Percentage</Id>
    <Name>Percentage for percentile</Name>
    <Description>Percentage for percentile (default 0.1 for MOE or 99.9 for HI).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsInverseDistribution</Id>
    <Name>Use inverse distribution to calculate percentile</Name>
    <Description>Calculate percentile via the complementary percentage of the inverse distribution (default: no). Description: E.g., P0.1 of MOE distribution is calculated via P99.9 of 1/MOE distribution. Note: This option is provided because percentile calculation in small data sets is asymmetric in both tails.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAdjustmentFactors</Id>
    <Name>Apply adjustment factors to the specified risk percentile</Name>
    <Description>Specify adjustment factors, e.g. based on expert knowledge elicitation, to a specified MOE percentile (default 0.1%). If the selected risk metric is HI, the adjustment factors should still be specified for the complementary percentile of MOE (e.g. P0.1 of MOE if P99.9 of HI is selected).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureAdjustmentFactorDistributionMethod</Id>
    <Name>Adjustment type related to exposure</Name>
    <Description>Specify the factor and/or distribution of the adjustment factor for the MOE percentile. Default is no adjustment. Alternatives are a fixed factor or an uncertainty distribution. If distributions are selected, default values are set based on EFSA cumulative risk reports 2020.</Description>
    <ValueType>AdjustmentFactorDistributionMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardAdjustmentFactorDistributionMethod</Id>
    <Name>Adjustment type related to hazard</Name>
    <Description>Specify the factor and/or distribution of the adjustment factor for the MOE percentile. Default is no adjustment. Alternatives are a fixed factor or an uncertainty distribution. If distributions are selected, default values are set based on EFSA cumulative risk reports 2020.</Description>
    <ValueType>AdjustmentFactorDistributionMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureParameterA</Id>
    <Name>Parameter A (Fixed factor, mean Lognormal or LogStudent-t, or shape parameter Beta or Gamma)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) the fixed adjustment factor; 2) for Lognormal or LogStudent-t, the mean of the underlying normal distribution; 3) For Beta or Gamma. the shape parameter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureParameterB</Id>
    <Name>Parameter B (standard deviation Lognormal or LogStudent-t or second shape parameter Beta or rate parameter Gamma)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) for Lognormal or LogStudent-t, the standard deviation of the underlying normal distribution; 2) For Beta, the second shape parameter; 3) for Gamma, the rate parameter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureParameterC</Id>
    <Name>Parameter C (Lower bound Beta, offset Gamma or Lognormal or degrees of freedom Logstudent-t)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) for Beta, the lower bound value; 2) for Gamma or Lognormal, the offset; 3) for LogStudent-t, the degrees of freedom.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureParameterD</Id>
    <Name>Parameter D (Upper bound Beta or offset LogStudent-t)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) for Beta, the upper bound value; 2) for LogStudent-t, the offset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardParameterA</Id>
    <Name>Parameter A (Fixed factor, mean Lognormal or LogStudent-t, or shape parameter Beta or Gamma)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) the fixed adjustment factor; 2) for Lognormal or LogStudent-t, the mean of the underlying normal distribution; 3) For Beta or Gamma. the shape parameter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardParameterB</Id>
    <Name>Parameter B (standard deviation Lognormal or LogStudent-t or second shape parameter Beta or rate parameter Gamma)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) for Lognormal or LogStudent-t, the standard deviation of the underlying normal distribution; 2) For Beta, the second shape parameter; 3) for Gamma, the rate parameter.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardParameterC</Id>
    <Name>Parameter C (Lower bound Beta, offset Gamma or Lognormal or degrees of freedom Logstudent-t)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) for Beta, the lower bound value; 2) for Gamma or Lognormal, the offset; 3) for LogStudent-t, the degrees of freedom.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardParameterD</Id>
    <Name>Parameter D (Upper bound Beta or offset LogStudent-t)</Name>
    <Description>This parameter can be: 1) for Beta, the upper bound value; 2) for LogStudent-t, the offset.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseBackgroundAdjustmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Restrict the adjustment to the non-focal (background) exposure contributions</Name>
    <Description>When exposures are calculated by combining focal food/substance concentrations with background concentrations, it may be appropriate to have separate adjustment for the foreground and background. A pragmatic solution agreed with EFSA is to estimate the contribution (c) of the focal exposure in the tail above the selected percentile. Note that the focal exposure may add over several active substances if the focal substance refers to multiple active substances (e.g. dithiocarbamates). If this option is selected, the adjustment factors are multiplied by (1-c), representing no adjustment for the focal part. </Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CalculateRisksByFood</Id>
    <Name>Calculate risks by modelled foods, substances or a combination of the two</Name>
    <Description>When the dose target level is external, dietary exposures are directly used as input to risks. Dietary exposures preserve the information of exposure by modelled foods, substances or the combination. Summarizing this information may time consuming.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Hazard characterisations (Target hazard doses) calculation settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDoseLevelType</Id>
    <Name>Target level</Name>
    <Description>Select to express hazard characterisations at external or internal exposure level. For an aggregate assessement, that is dietary and nondietary exposure data are combined, the target dose level is always internal. When only dietary exposures are available, the target dose level is optional, i.c. external or internal. </Description>
    <ValueType>TargetLevelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDosesCalculationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Method</Name>
    <Description>Choose method for computing the hazard characterisations: from in-vivo or in-vitro points of departure or both.</Description>
    <ValueType>TargetDosesCalculationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>PointOfDeparture</Id>
    <Name>Expression type</Name>
    <Description>Specifies how hazard characterisations are expressed: as BMD, as NOAEL, or the expression type is ignored.</Description>
    <ValueType>PointOfDeparture</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictToCriticalEffect</Id>
    <Name>Consider critical effect</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the analysis should look at critical effects such as specified in the Hazard characterisation data source.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TargetDoseSelectionMethod</Id>
    <Name>Selection method in case of multiple candidate hazard characterisations</Name>
    <Description>Choose either the most toxic (default) or an aggregated hazard characterisation when in nominal runs there are multiple available candidates. In uncertainty runs, multiple candidates are resampled.</Description>
    <ValueType>TargetDoseSelectionMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImputeMissingHazardDoses</Id>
    <Name>Impute missing hazard characterisations</Name>
    <Description>If checked, missing hazard characterisations are imputed based on Munro NOELs or on other available points of departure.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>HazardDoseImputationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Imputation method</Name>
    <Description>Imputation of Hazard characterisations: use low percentile (P5) or unbiased central estimate from either the Munro set or the available POD collection.</Description>
    <IsAdvanced>true</IsAdvanced>
    <ValueType>HazardDoseImputationMethodType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseDoseResponseModels</Id>
    <Name>Use BMDs from dose response models</Name>
    <Description>If checked, preferably BMDs from dose response models will be used. If these data are not available, other POD data are used.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseInterSpeciesConversionFactors</Id>
    <Name>Use inter-species conversions</Name>
    <Description>Use inter-species conversion factors (default value, e.g. 10, or data).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseIntraSpeciesConversionFactors</Id>
    <Name>Use intra-species factors</Name>
    <Description>Use intra-species conversion factors (default value, e.g. 10, or data).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseAdditionalAssessmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Use additional assessment factor</Name>
    <Description>Use additional assessment factor for extrapolation of PODs to (human) hazard characterisations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>AdditionalAssessmentFactor</Id>
    <Name>Additional assessment factor</Name>
    <Description>Additional assessment factor for extrapolation of PODs to (human) hazard characterisations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>


  <!-- Non-dietary settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MatchSpecificIndividuals</Id>
    <Name>Match non-dietary to dietary survey individuals</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the individuals of one or more non-dietary surveys should be matched to individuals in the dietary survey according to the individual codes (idIndividual). If unchecked, nondietary exposures are randomly allocated to dietary survey individuals.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsCorrelationBetweenIndividuals</Id>
    <Name>Match individuals of multiple non-dietary surveys</Name>
    <Description>If checked, exposures from identical individuals in non-dietary surveys are aggregated to obtain the overall nondietary exposures. If unchecked, exposures from random individuals in all non-dietary surveys are aggregated.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Dietary intake calculation settings  -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DietaryIntakeCalculationTier</Id>
    <Name>Dietary exposure calculation tier</Name>
    <Description>A tier is a pre-specified set of model configurations. By selecting a model tier, MCRA automatically sets all model settings in this module according to this tier. Note that currently tier setting may need to be performed separately in sub-modules. Use the Custom tier when you want to manually set each model setting.</Description>
    <ValueType>DietaryIntakeCalculationTier</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImputeExposureDistributions</Id>
    <Name>Impute exposure distributions</Name>
    <Description>Impute exposure distributions for substances with missing concentrations.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsDistribution</Id>
    <Name>Use distribution</Name>
    <Description>Probabilistic specifications of processing factors will be used</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>AllowHigherThanOne</Id>
    <Name>Ignore processing factors less than 1</Name>
    <Description>This setting will suppress the use of processing factors lower than 1 (it is used in the EFSA 2012 Pessimistic tier).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SingleValueDietaryExposureCalculationMethod</Id>
    <Name>Single value dietary exposure calculation method</Name>
    <Description>Method for computing single value dietary exposures.</Description>
    <ValueType>SingleValueDietaryExposuresCalculationMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ModelledFoodsCalculationSource</Id>
    <Name>Derived modelled foods for concentration source</Name>
    <Description>The derived modelled foods for the specified concentration source that is used in the conversion algorithm to determine for which modelled food concentrations are available. This source is 1) a single value concentrations data source  or 2) a sampled concentrations data source.</Description>
    <ValueType>ModelledFoodsCalculationSource</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Diagnostics in DietaryExposure settings Dto-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>VariabilityDiagnosticsAnalysis</Id>
    <Name>Include diagnostics analysis for variability</Name>
    <Description>For each percentile the variability (standard deviation) of the estimated percentiles versus sample size are plotted.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Effect settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MultipleEffects</Id>
    <Name>Multiple effects analysis</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether the analysis should consider multiple effects. Otherwise, a single focal effect should be selected.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeFocalEffect</Id>
    <Name>Focal effect</Name>
    <Description>The main (health) effect of interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeReferenceCompound</Id>
    <Name>Index substance</Name>
    <Description>The substance of interest or index substance.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeResponse</Id>
    <Name>Response</Name>
    <Description>The response of interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodesResponses</Id>
    <Name>Response(s)</Name>
    <Description>The response(s) of interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IncludeAopNetwork</Id>
    <Name>Include related effects of AOP network</Name>
    <Description>Include all related key events of the AOP network.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeAopNetwork</Id>
    <Name>AOP Network</Name>
    <Description>The AOP networks of interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RestrictAopByFocalUpstreamEffect</Id>
    <Name>Restrict AOP network by focal upstream event</Name>
    <Description>Restrict the AOP network to a specific sub-network, containing only the AOPs that include both the focal key event (KE) defined here (which must be upstream of the AO) and the focal effect (adverse outcome, AO).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeFocalUpstreamEffect</Id>
    <Name>Focal upstream event</Name>
    <Description>The focal key event used for restricting the AOP network to a specific sub-network of interest.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Substance settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CompoundGroupSelectionMethod</Id>
    <Name>Cumulative assessment group definition</Name>
    <Description>The method used to determine the substances of the effect.</Description>
    <ValueType>CompoundGroupSelectionMethodType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CombinationMethodMembershipInfoAndPodPresence</Id>
    <Name>Combination method memberships from available PODs and in-silico data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether to take the intersection or the union of the set of substances with available PoDs and the set of substances with positive/probable (in-silico) membership score.</Description>
    <ValueType>CombinationMethodMembershipInfoAndPodPresence</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterByCertainAssessmentGroupMembership</Id>
    <Name>Filter by certain assessment group membership</Name>
    <Description>Filter substances by certain assessment group membership.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FilterByPossibleAssessmentGroupMembership</Id>
    <Name>Filter by possible assessment group membership</Name>
    <Description>Filter substances by possible assessment group membership.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodesSubstances</Id>
    <Name>The substances that will be used</Name>
    <Description>The substances scope will be restricted to the substances selected here</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Intake model settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IntakeModelType</Id>
    <Name>Model type</Name>
    <Description>The parametric model for between-and within-individual variation, and possibly covariates.</Description>
    <ValueType>IntakeModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>TransformType</Id>
    <Name>Transformation</Name>
    <Description>The data transformation used to approximate normality for amounts.</Description>
    <ValueType>TransformType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>GridPrecision</Id>
    <Name>Grid precision frequency model</Name>
    <Description>The discrete frequency distribution (ISUF) is approximated via a number of classes.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfIterations</Id>
    <Name>Number of iterations (x 1000)</Name>
    <Description>The number of iterations that is used to estimate the discrete frequency distribution for the ISUF model.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SplineFit</Id>
    <Name>Spline-fit</Name>
    <Description>To achieve a better normality, a second transformation is performed: a spline function is fitted to the logarithmically or power transformed data as a function of the normal Blom scores.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CovariateModelling</Id>
    <Name>Covariate modelling</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether to model exposures as a function of covariates at individual level.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>FirstModelThenAdd</Id>
    <Name>Model-then-add</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether to create separate exposure models for specific groups of modelled foods (model-then-add).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Dispersion</Id>
    <Name>Frequency model dispersion</Name>
    <Description>Frequency model dispersion estimate for (only relevant for data with only 1 day per individual).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>VarianceRatio</Id>
    <Name>Amounts model: variance ratio (between/within)</Name>
    <Description>Estimate of the ratio of the variance components of the amounts model (only relevant for data with only 1 day per individual)</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IntakeModelsPerCategory</Id>
    <Name>Model-then-add sub-category models</Name>
    <Description>Sub-model specifications for foods groups that should be modelled separately.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Kinetic model settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>OralAbsorptionFactorForDietaryExposure</Id>
    <Name>Default oral absorption factor for dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, dietary exposures (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose .</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>OralAbsorptionFactor</Id>
    <Name>Default oral absorption factor for non-dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, non-dietary oral exposures (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DermalAbsorptionFactor</Id>
    <Name>Default dermal absorption factor for non-dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, dermal exposures (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>InhalationAbsorptionFactor</Id>
    <Name>Default inhalation absorption factor for non-dietary exposure</Name>
    <Description>When there is no kinetic model and absorption factors are not specified in file, inhalation exposures (external doses) are multiplied by this factor to determine the absorbed (internal) dose.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>InternalModelType</Id>
    <Name>Specify the type of kinetic model</Name>
    <Description>Specify the type of model to convert external exposure to the internal level.</Description>
    <ValueType>InternalModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeKineticModel</Id>
    <Name>Kinetic model</Name>
    <Description>Code Kinetic Model.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodeCompartment</Id>
    <Name>Biological matrix</Name>
    <Description>Biological matrix.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfDays</Id>
    <Name>Number of days </Name>
    <Description>The number of days.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfDosesPerDay</Id>
    <Name>Number of events per day for the ORAL dietary dose</Name>
    <Description>The daily dose is administered in equal portions (dose / number of events) per event.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfDosesPerDayNonDietaryOral</Id>
    <Name>Number of events per day for the ORAL nondietary dose</Name>
    <Description>The daily dose is administered in equal portions (dose / number of events) per event.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfDosesPerDayNonDietaryDermal</Id>
    <Name>Number of events per day for the DERMAL nondietary dose</Name>
    <Description>The daily dose is administered in equal portions (dose / number of events) per event.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfDosesPerDayNonDietaryInhalation</Id>
    <Name>Number of events per day for the INHALATION nondietary dose</Name>
    <Description>The daily dose is administered in equal portions (dose / number of events) per event.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NonStationaryPeriod</Id>
    <Name>Number of initial days skipped</Name>
    <Description>This period is skipped in the calculation of the mean internal exposure.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseParameterVariability</Id>
    <Name>Use parameter variability</Name>
    <Description>When specified, use parameter variability.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SpecifyEvents</Id>
    <Name>Specify events</Name>
    <Description>if checked, a sequence of hours can be specified, otherswise the events are derived based on the number of doses per day.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SelectedEvents</Id>
    <Name>Specify the hours (events).</Name>
    <Description>Specify the hours (events) on which a dose is applied. Allowed numbers are 1, 2, 3, 4,..., 24 separated by spaces.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>


  <!-- Mixture selection -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureApproachType</Id>
    <Name>Substance weighting</Name>
    <Description>Risk based (exposures in equivalents of the reference substance) or standardised (standardised exposures per substance have variance 1).</Description>
    <ValueType>ExposureApproachType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfMixtures</Id>
    <Name>SNMU: number of components</Name>
    <Description>The number of components to select in SNMU.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MixtureSelectionSparsenessConstraint</Id>
    <Name>Sparseness parameter</Name>
    <Description>Sparseness parameter. Value between 0 (not sparse, many substances) and 1 (sparse, few substances).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MixtureSelectionIterations</Id>
    <Name>Iterations</Name>
    <Description>Maximum number of iterations, e.g. 1000.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MixtureSelectionRandomSeed</Id>
    <Name>Seed for pseudo-random number generator.</Name>
    <Description>Random seed for initialising matrix W and H.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MixtureSelectionConvergenceCriterium</Id>
    <Name>Convergence criterion</Name>
    <Description>Convergence criterion for factorisation algorithm.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MixtureSelectionRatioCutOff</Id>
    <Name>Cutoff MCR</Name>
    <Description>For selection of individual(day) exposures with maximum cumulative ratio (MCR = total exposure/maximum) above the cutoff.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MixtureSelectionTotalExposureCutOff</Id>
    <Name>Cutoff percentage in population ranked on total exposure</Name>
    <Description>For selection of individual(day) exposures above the cutoff percentage in the set of individual(day)s ranked on total exposure.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>InternalConcentrationType</Id>
    <Name>Internal concentration</Name>
    <Description>Internal concentrations are derived form dietary and/or non-dietary concentrations and aggregated using a kinetic or absorption factor model or are human monitoring concentrations.</Description>
    <ValueType>InternalConcentrationType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfClusters</Id>
    <Name>Number of clusters</Name>
    <Description>Number of clusters for hierarchical cluster analysis or clustering minimizing within-cluster variance (k-means).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ClusterMethodType</Id>
    <Name>Method</Name>
    <Description>After component selection, a clustering maybe applied on the individuals coefficents matrix V (or H) using K-Means or hierarchical clustering to identify populations sub-groupings.</Description>
    <ValueType>ClusterMethodType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>AutomaticallyDeterminationOfClusters</Id>
    <Name>Determine number of clusters automatically</Name>
    <Description>For hierarchical clustering the number of clusters is determined automatically.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NetworkAnalysisType</Id>
    <Name>Network analysis typemethod</Name>
    <Description>Network analysis on the substance x component (U) matrix.</Description>
    <ValueType>NetworkAnalysisType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Monte Carlo settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RandomSeed</Id>
    <Name>Seed for pseudo-random number generator</Name>
    <Description>0 will use a pseudo-random seed in each run, seeds &gt; 0 will provide the same results in a repeated run.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfMonteCarloIterations</Id>
    <Name>Monte Carlo iterations</Name>
    <Description>The number of iterations for Monte Carlo simulations, e.g. 100.000 (maximum is 100.000).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsSurveySampling</Id>
    <Name>Iterate survey</Name>
    <Description>Instead of (re-)sampling the individual days, loop over the entire survey (= 1 iteration). The number of iterations for a survey is calculated as round (number of Monte Carlo iterations /(number of individuals * surveys days)).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Output detail settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsDetailedOutput</Id>
    <Name>Include drill-down on 9 individuals around specified percentile.</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether drilldown on 9 individuals is to be included in the output.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SummarizeSimulatedData</Id>
    <Name>Summarize simulated data</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether a summary of the simulated consumptions and concentrations should be included in the output.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>StoreIndividualDayIntakes</Id>
    <Name>Store simulated individual day exposures</Name>
    <Description>Store the simulated individual day exposures. If unchecked, no additional output will be generated. If checked, the output will contain an additional section with the simulated individual day exposures.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>SelectedPercentiles</Id>
    <Name>Show percentiles for</Name>
    <Description>Give specific percentiles of exposure distribution (%), e.g. 50 90 95 97.5 99 (space separated).</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>PercentageForDrilldown</Id>
    <Name>Percentage for drilldown</Name>
    <Description>Gives detailed output for nine individuals near this percentile of the exposure distribution.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>PercentageForUpperTail</Id>
    <Name>Percentage for upper tail</Name>
    <Description>Gives detailed output for this upper percentage of the exposure distribution.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureMethod</Id>
    <Name>Show % of population below level(s)</Name>
    <Description>This setting is used for reporting the percentages of individuals (chronic) or individual days (acute) exceeding certain exposure levels. These exposure levels can be generated automatically based on the observed exposures (Automatic, default) or specified explicitly (Manual).</Description>
    <ValueType>ExposureMethod</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureLevels</Id>
    <Name>Exposure levels</Name>
    <Description>Specify exposure levels for which to give the percentage of exposure below these levels, e.g. 1 10 50 100 200 500.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <!--Kan weg denk ik-->
  <!--<SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExposureInterpretation</Id>
    <Name>Exposure levels are</Name>
    <Description>Specify whether exposure levels are absolute or percentages of ARfD/ADI (Obsolete).</Description>
  </SettingsItem>-->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>Intervals</Id>
    <Name>Number of levels of covariable to predict exposure</Name>
    <Description>Specify the number of levels, e.g. 20. The range of the covariable is divided by the number of levels: range = (max - min)/levels. For these covariable levels exposures are predicted.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ExtraPredictionLevels</Id>
    <Name>Predict exposure at extra covariable levels</Name>
    <Description>Specify specific prediction levels in addition to the automatically generated prediction levels (space separated).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>LowerPercentage</Id>
    <Name>Lower percentage for variability (%)</Name>
    <Description>The default value of 25% may be overruled.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UpperPercentage</Id>
    <Name>Upper percentage for variability (%)</Name>
    <Description>The default value of 75% may be overruled.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>OutputSections</Id>
    <Name>Section class names filter</Name>
    <Description>The processed sections can be filtered based on the section class names in this field (separated by spaces). If empty, no filter is applied. When selecting only a child section, also include parent section(s). Starting this field with an exclamation mark inverts the filter and excludes given sections.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MaximumCumulativeRatioCutOff</Id>
    <Name>Display ratio total exposure/ maximum (in MCR plot)</Name>
    <Description>For MCR plot: specify ratio total exposure/ maximum for individual(day) exposures .</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MaximumCumulativeRatioPercentiles</Id>
    <Name>Show tail percentiles (MCR plot) for:</Name>
    <Description>Give specific percentiles of exposure distribution (%), e.g. 97.5 99 (space separated).</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MaximumCumulativeRatioMinimumPercentage</Id>
    <Name>Set minimum percentage contribution per substance to the tail exposure (MCR plot)</Name>
    <Description>Set minimum percentage contribution per substance to the tail exposure.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <!-- Population settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CodePopulation</Id>
    <Name>Population</Name>
    <Description>Specifies which population is selected.</Description>
    <ValueType>AlphaNumeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Screening settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DietaryExposuresDetailsLevel</Id>
    <Name>Details level dietary exposures</Name>
    <Description>Level of detail for summarizing dietary exposure/intakes.</Description>
    <ValueType>DietaryExposuresDetailsLevel</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsScreening</Id>
    <Name>Apply exposure screening</Name>
    <Description>Apply exposure screening results as a first step in full run, and restrict output regarding foods as eaten to risk drivers.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CriticalExposurePercentage</Id>
    <Name>Percentage defining the exposure percentile of interest per food-as-eaten/food-as-measured/substance combination</Name>
    <Description>Percentage defining the exposure percentile of interest per food-as-eaten/food-as-measured/substance combination.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CumulativeSelectionPercentage</Id>
    <Name>Include risk drivers to include minimally a percentage</Name>
    <Description>The selection criterion for the risk drivers. The cumulative contribution percentage of the selected risk drivers will be this percentage.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ImportanceLor</Id>
    <Name>Censored value replacement: factor x LOR</Name>
    <Description>A constant between 0 and 1. A value 0 can be used for an optimistic screening (LOR not used). Note that a factor 0.5 (pessimistic) may result in many and often high contributions from food-substance combinations with only censored values.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>

  <!-- Uncertainty analysis settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DoUncertaintyAnalysis</Id>
    <Name>Perform uncertainty analysis</Name>
    <Description>In probabilistic risk assessment of dietary exposure, distributions describe the variability in consumption within a given population of individuals and the variability of the occurrence and level of substances in the consumed foods. However, these calculations do not consider the amount of uncertainty that is due to the limited size of the underlying datasets.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfIterationsPerResampledSet</Id>
    <Name>Monte Carlo iterations per uncertainty run</Name>
    <Description>Specifies the number of Monte Carlo iterations in each uncertainty cycle (default 10.000).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>NumberOfResampleCycles</Id>
    <Name>Iterations uncertainty analysis</Name>
    <Description>Specifies the number of uncertainty cycles (default 100).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleConcentrations</Id>
    <Name>Resample concentrations</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether concentrations are resampled by empirical bootstrap or using a parametric uncertainty model.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>IsParametric</Id>
    <Name>Parametric uncertainty</Name>
    <Description>For resample concentrations: specifies whether the uncertainty assessment is based on a parametric approach.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UncertaintyType</Id>
    <Name>Concentration modelling uncertainty method</Name>
    <Description>For resample concentrations: specifies whether the uncertainty assessment is based on a parametric approach or empirical bootstrapping.</Description>
    <ValueType>UncertaintyType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleNonDietaryExposures</Id>
    <Name>Resample non-dietary exposures</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether non-dietary exposures are resampled. Note that non-dietary uncertainty is only ignored when individual uncertainty is set to false (uncheck box: do NOT resample individuals).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ResampleIndividuals</Id>
    <Name>Resample individuals</Name>
    <Description>Individual data are resampled from the original database using the bootstrap methodology (Efron 1979, Efron &amp; Tibshirani 1993).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DoUncertaintyFactorial</Id>
    <Name>Perform uncertainty factorial</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether a complete factorial is performed over all selected sources of uncertainty.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSamplePortions</Id>
    <Name>Resample portion sizes</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether portion sizes should be resampled based on food consumption quantification data, see (Souverein et al. 2011).</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleProcessingFactors</Id>
    <Name>Resample processing factors</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether processing factors are resampled from a parametric uncertainty distribution.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleAssessmentGroupMemberships</Id>
    <Name>Resample assessment group memberships</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether assessment group memberships of substances should be resampled using the assessment group membership probabilities.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleImputationExposureDistributions</Id>
    <Name>Resample imputation exposure distributions</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether to resample the imputated exposure distributions.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleRPFs</Id>
    <Name>Resample hazard characterisations or RPFs</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether to resample the hazard characterisations or relative potency factors. Requires hazard characterisation or RPF uncertainty to be quantified in DoseResponseModelsUncertain or RelativePotencyFactorsUncertain tables.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleInterspecies</Id>
    <Name>Resample inter-species factor</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether inter-species factors are resampled from a parametric uncertainty distribution.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleIntraSpecies</Id>
    <Name>Resample intra-species factor</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether intra-species factors are resampled from a parametric uncertainty distribution.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ResampleKineticModelParameters</Id>
    <Name>Resample kinetic model parameter values</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether kinetic model parameter values are resampled.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>ReSampleParameterValues</Id>
    <Name>Resample dose response model parameter values</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether dose response model parameter values are resampled from the list of parameter values.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>RecomputeOccurrencePatterns</Id>
    <Name>Recompute occurrence patterns</Name>
    <Description>Specifies whether occurrence patterns should be recomputed in the uncertainty runs.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UncertaintyLowerBound</Id>
    <Name>Lower uncertainty limit (%)</Name>
    <Description>Percentage lower bound, e.g. 2.5%.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UncertaintyUpperBound</Id>
    <Name>Upper uncertainty limit (%)</Name>
    <Description>Percentage upper bound, e.g. 97.5%.</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>


  <!-- Unit variability settings -->
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UseUnitVariability</Id>
    <Name>Use unit variability</Name>
    <Description>Controls whether to use unit variability.</Description>
    <ValueType>Boolean</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UnitVariabilityModel</Id>
    <Name>Unit variability model</Name>
    <Description>Describes variation between single units when concentration data are from composite samples.</Description>
    <ValueType>UnitVariabilityModelType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>EstimatesNature</Id>
    <Name>Estimates nature</Name>
    <Description>Simulated unit concentrations can be higher or lower than composite value (realistic) or only equal or higher (conservative).</Description>
    <ValueType>EstimatesNature</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>UnitVariabilityType</Id>
    <Name>Unit variability parameter</Name>
    <Description>Use Coefficient of variation or Variability factor, specified in VariabilityFactor table.</Description>
    <ValueType>UnitVariabilityType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>MeanValueCorrectionType</Id>
    <Name>Mean of LogNormal simulated values (biasing)</Name>
    <Description>Unbiased: correct unit simulations for difference between median and mean.</Description>
    <ValueType>MeanValueCorrectionType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DefaultFactorLow</Id>
    <Name>Default variability factor for unit weight &lt;= 25g</Name>
    <Description>Default variability factor 1 (unit weight &lt;= 25 g, small crops). Still requires specification of unit weight (FoodProperties table) and, in case of beta model, also the Number of units in a composite sample (UnitVariability table).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>DefaultFactorMid</Id>
    <Name>Default variability factor for unit weight &gt; 25g</Name>
    <Description>Default variability factor 5 (unit weight &gt; 25 g, medium/large crops). Still requires specification of unit weight (FoodProperties table) and, in case of beta model, also the Number of units in a composite sample (UnitVariability table).</Description>
    <ValueType>Numeric</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
  <SettingsItem>
    <Id>CorrelationType</Id>
    <Name>Correlation between substances on the same units</Name>
    <Description>Specifies the type of correlation between substances on the same units; no correlation or full correlation.</Description>
    <ValueType>UnitVariabilityCorrelationType</ValueType>
  </SettingsItem>
</SettingsItems>
